Start with a few things. One, from a
good program down there in Georgia, over
40 starts, I believe.
Came up big in some of the biggest games
for that program that's used to playing
in a lot of big games. He gets the ball
and just telling you just the the
physical attributes and then the fact
that I got to know him a little bit in
terms of his personality when we went
down there for the pro day. Had a great
dinner with him. Great interaction and
the seriousness he has about football.
Um the focus he has as a young man. I
was really impressed by that and you
could just tell there's some grit there
about him and a willingness to get
better and I can't wait to get him to
Joe and uh Simo in terms of
those guys coaching him up and seeing
where it plays out, but like really
really excited for him and you know,
congratulations to his family and
congratulations to him and you know,
coach Smart and the Georgia program for,
you know, helping that young man on his
journey. Questions?
>> [clears throat]
>> What kind of vision do you have for him
fitting into your defense? The main
thing, you know, we talked to
Omar and his staff. We we just we just
want good football players. And you
know, then you know, we try to put them
in by position, but just in general,
defensive back, a good football player,
someone that can tackle, someone that
has some speed and explosiveness. We're
trying to be an explosive unit out there
on the field. So, those are all traits
that he has and then having a football
IQ when you talk ball to him, there's a
a level of intelligence there that you
know, is intriguing and knowing the
system he came from,
that makes it even more intriguing.
Um so, but like to say where he's going
to be, just good football player and you
know, like most of those guys, you know,
you got to start you just got to play
hard, earn the trust of the veterans and
then we'll see how it plays out in
September. You talked about the
physicality of Porter last week when you
talked with you. What's the biggest
thing that stood out to you about him
and where where does it show? Did you
guys see the the size? I mean, this is I
mean, when you meet him,
I mean, he he's he's well put together
in terms of his build.
Again, I I love the seriousness on his
face. You know, I'm not trying to make a
read on just a kid a guy
how he's going to play as a football
player by his demeanor, but his demeanor
is what we're looking for. You know, I
think it's I know it's going to fit the
mold of what we're trying to shape here
with the Pittsburgh defense. So, and
what has been in the past, but it's just
really good demeanor about this guy and
he has all the attributes to be a real
physical presence out there on the
perimeter. When you have a guy that
tests fast like this, how do you get him
to play fast at the NFL level quickly?
You know, playing fast is playing with
some anticipation and that's a big role
for the coaches in terms of helping
eliminate variables for the players.
Uh that's what I talked to the guys
about in order for us to play fast as a
defense as a unit, it's our job to help
eliminate some variables for you so that
you get, you know, because
what we do is different. We're playing
defense. The offense calls plays. It's a
little bit different and so that that's
the that's the way and he'll get that
from reps, you know, watching film,
experiences, you know, he's going to
have to have some experiences out there
on the field to learn from and it'll
come for him.
You got an Alabama receiver and now a
Georgia cornerback. Are you looking
forward to some of these battles between
the rookies and Cam Sutton? Well, I
mean, those they'll be competitive, I'm
sure I'm sure, but they'll find out once
they get here, nobody cares.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean, not not I mean, you know, a lot
of respect for those guys and they know
it's a joke, but you know,
you know, it's it's it's go time now.
How how ideal of a situation is it for
him to walk in here with Jaylen and
Jamal kind of being mentors with Joey
Porter, I guess at [clears throat] this
point? You have to ask him, but you
know, the the main thing for me is
veteran
players
help. They helped me on my path in the
league when I was a coach, I learned a
lot from, you know, a couple great
players when I was at my first stop and
I'm sure it's tenfold for the the
players when they learn from those guys
because they spend more time with them
in the locker room, you know, going out
to dinner and stuff. So, I'm sure
they're going to pick their brain. I
mean,
it is probably a lot more than just the
football part. It's probably about the,
you know, body how to maintain your
body,
time management because, you know, it's
it's totally different. Everything was
laid out in college and now you have it
now where you're going to have a lot of
free time and how do you manage your
time and then how do you say no? I mean,
that's going to be a big part of it. So,
I I'm I'm sure just the the
personalities I've met so far in the
locker room, it's going to be a great
benefit for them and then the football
part, you know, we it's our
responsibility to coach those guys and
then put them in the right position to
be successful and the veterans will give
them some insight, I'm sure I'm sure.
Coach T, you guys have some big corners
and some veteran guys. Did you highlight
someone with his elite speed as
something that you were looking for to
add to the room?
I mean, when you when you look at the
position in terms of what we value,
in terms of what we're trying the ideal
is, you know, high weight speed. That's
what the league is all about. I would
say pretty much at every position is
high weight speed. And so, if you got
someone that's big, has some
length,
can run and has some size to him, it's a
it's it's just it's a positive,
especially
going back to it, our division. Our
division and then also dealing with the
teams that we want to face if we we're
fortunate enough to get to, you know,
playoff time, the teams that
consistently are in the playoffs, you
need those physical guys to
to combat what they do on offense. And
more importantly, special And then not
more importantly, but also on special
teams. Two more. Do you How do you How
do you feel that he plays in man
coverage?
How
>> [laughter]
>> I mean, how would I give the specifics
about that? I'm
He has all the skill the tools to do
what we're going to ask him to do
because I know this, we're going to play
some man, we're going to play some zone.
So, I mean, he he's a good football
player and you know, I mean, all the
rookies have a ways to go and so doesn't
that's not you need to anybody from
tonight, I mean, or last night. So, but
I'm very pleased to have him on our on
our team and I like his skill set. In
2024, he led Georgia with interceptions
and forced fumbles this year and PBUs.
How did that ball production show up on
tape and how attractive is the ball
production that he put up in this
system?
You know, we mentioned it the first day
we talked to the guys,
it's about the ball.
You got I mean, if you get the ball,
I tell the players like, you know, cuz
there's no depth chart right now.
Um
if it's open audition for ball hawks. If
you can get the ball and you show a
consistency getting the ball in practice
and preseason,
they'll we'll find a way for you. It's
going to be hard for you not to make the
team. It's about the ball. If we get
anytime we could take away possession
from the offense, especially with these
fourth downs that come up that adds onto
the possessions, it's so big and it's
always been big and it leads it's a big
um factor in winning games. So, that's
that's that's high that's high on our
checklist for every position. All right,
thank you, coach. Thank you.
>> [clears throat]